kidscantravel.com 2007-08-14

# Privacy | kids can travel

|   | 

The contents of this statement are in accordance with Italian law governing Data Protection, [art.13 of Decree law No.196 dated June 30, 2003](http://www.camera.it/parlam/leggi/deleghe/testi/03196dl.htm). This English-language translation has been legalized by the Court of Monza, Italy as certified below and is in conformity with the Italian-language original.

kidscantravel.com is committed to protecting your privacy. Please read the kidscantravel.com Privacy policy below to obtain user information with regard to: 

  1. [Definitions](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#a)
  2. [Collection of information](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#b): [b.1 anonymous navigation information](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#b1), [b.2 personal information](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#b2), [b.3 IP addresses, cookies e web beacons](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#b3)
  3. [Usage of personal information](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#c)
  4. [Right of refusal](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#d)
  5. [Communicating and divulging data](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#e)
  6. [User rights](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#f)
  7. [Exercising user rights](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#g)
  8. [Handling of personal information](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#h)
  9. [Changes to the Policy policy](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#i)
  10. [Links](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#j)
  11. [Certification of translation](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#k)

**a. Definitions**  
Personal information includes any information relating to a natural person, juridical person, body or association, identified or identifiable, even indirectly, by means of reference to said information, including therein a personal identification number. Identifying information is personal information that leads to the direct identification of the user.  
Sensitive information is personal information that reveals the user's racial and ethnic origin, religious, philosophical, political, union or other beliefs, affiliations, associations or memberships, as well as personal data that reveals the user's state of health or sexual inclinations.  
Usage of personal information consists of any action (activity) or series of actions to collect, record, organize, maintain, consult, process, modify, select, extract, compare, use, link, block, communicate, share, cancel and destroy said information.  

**b. Collection of information** **:[b1. anonymous navigation information](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#b1), [b.2 personal information](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#b2), [b.3 IP addresses, cookies and web beacons](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#b3) **

Personal information pertaining to the user is stored on an appropriately protected server in Italy where it remains for the time strictly necessary to transmit the communication or supply the services as indicated herein. Access to said server is strictly limited to personnel authorized to operate the server and for other corporate purposes. Strict controls and access protocols are in force. 

Personal information collected by kidscantravel.com can be divided into two categories:

**b1. anonymous navigation information**  
The collection of a certain amount of personal information is inherent in Internet navigation. kidscantravel.com collects certain standard anonymous navigation information that the user's browser (navigation system) sends to every website visited such as the user's [IP (Internet Protocol) address](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#b3), referring Web site address, URL address of the resources requested, access time, browser type and language, size of the file obtained in response, type of information obtained, numerical code indicating the status of the response given by the server and other user operating system related indexes. 

kidscantravel.com uses the IP address for administrative purposes as well as provide kidscantravel.com advertisers with aggregated anonymous navigation information. The collection of the above information cannot be construed to lead to the disclosure of user identifying or user sensitive information such as **name** , **address** or any other personal information that would reveal user sensitive information.  
kidscantravel.com collects anonymous navigation information such as, browser version, geographical location of the computer or server, pages viewed, links clicked, and any other actions (activity) undertaken while visiting the website. [Cookies](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#b3) and [web beacons](http://www.kidscantravel.com/privacy/index.html#b3) are utilized to collect said information. kidscantravel.com uses cookies to customize content, optimize advertising for example through the frequency variable that allows the user to view an advertising message only a certain number of times, trace user behavior profiles based on navigation patterns followed during the course of visits to the site and update statistics that record the visits received by the user. All web traffic statistics arising from the use of cookies are subject primarily to two variables: a) the user has enabled the cookie support function available in their browser and b) subsequent connections are carried out by means of the same browser. Generally, Internet browsers are set to accept cookies. The user may disable cookies, however this may limit usage of the site. Cookies may be disabled by means of the apposite browser functionality.

Web beacons enable kidscantravel.com to determine, in an anonymous manner, for example, whether and how many times a particular web page has been viewed. Web beacons are also be utilized to verify whether a request by the user to obtain additional information on a given promotion has been fulfilled.   
Anonymous navigation information collected or acquired by the means outlined above is not utilized to identify the user or obtain user sensitive information such as user **name** , **address** or any other personal information that would reveal user sensitive information.  
kidscantravel.com collects, directly or indirectly, said anonymous navigation information for the efficient operation of the site, to deliver services requested by the user, and improve the efficacy and quality of the kidscantravel.com service.  
Moreover said anonymous navigation information is used for statistical purposes, to customize content and to improve the efficacy of those advertising campaigns associated with the service provided by kidscantravel.com, and may also be shared with third parties for commercial purposes.  
The user may send any inquiries to [privacy@kidscantravel.com](mailto:privacy@kidscantravel.com). 

**b2. Personal Information**  
With the exception of that set out in b.1. of this Privacy policy, kidscantravel.com requests the user register to access the following functionality: **newsletter** , **contests and games** , **miniguide** , **reader ratings** as well as **email a page to a friend**. Personal information is collected, retained and processed exclusively to provide and carry out those services requested by the user. Registration is not compulsory. Failure to register solely limits the user's ability to access those services for which registration is required and makes it impossible for kidscantravel.com to provide said services. The user may modify and/or cancel their registration and withdraw personal information at any time using the modification and cancellation procedures available on the site, as well as that provided in the newsletter. kidscantravel.com requires email confirmation from the user prior to effecting any registrations, modifications or cancellations. The user may contact [privacy@kidscantravel.com](mailto:privacy@kidscantravel.com) should they encounter any registration, modification or cancellation difficulties. Registration consists of the user providing their email address, country of residence, year of birth, sex, and number of children to kidscantravel.com so as to:  

* receive thematic **newsletters** and/or any offers made by its commercial partners. 
* access **contest and games** as well as receive notification of any prizes won as a result of participation in said activities organized by kidscantravel.com; 
* access the **miniguide** , which enables the user to create a customized guide/itinerary; 
* access **reader ratings** to evaluate a destination, activity or accommodation as well as express interest in information on specific travel related topics; 
* send a page to third parties, accomplished by clicking on the text " **email this page** " located in the right-hand column of each page consenting this functionality.
  
The user that [registers](http://www.kidscantravel.com/legal/index.html#6c) with kidscantravel.com is solely responsible for the safekeeping of the information provided, even as regards those activities put into being as a result of their use. 

**b3. IP addresses, cookies and web beacons**  
**IP addresses** are 32 bit numbers that unequivocally represent those sending or receiving data via the Internet. IP addresses are generally expressed as a series of four numbers each separated by a full stop, each of the four numbers may vary from 0 to 255. Any communication that takes place on the Internet must include the sender and recipient's IP address.  
**Cookies** are small pieces of information stored by the computers of the user browsing the Internet and allow websites to remember user activity and visits to a site. Cookies are stored on the hard drive of the computer the user has utilized to connect to a given website and are recognized by said website each time the user reconnects to said website.  
**Web beacons** are part of the website instrumentation. In general, all electronic images that are part of the web page, including advertising banners, can operate as web beacons.   

**c. Usage of personal information**  
Personal information related to the user consensually provided (email address and password, country of residence, year of birth, sex, and number of children) or collected (anonymous navigation information) whilst browsing in kidscantravel.com is used, even by means of electronic tools and procedures, for the following purposes:  

* those directly associated with and/or instrumental to providing and managing the [service](http://www.kidscantravel.com/legal/index.html#1); the usage of personal information is strictly necessary and exclusively aimed at providing information regarding the services offered, and carrying out and satisfying requests formulated by the user in accordance with the purposes and uses of the site; 
* fulfill those obligations set out by the law and EU community regulations; 
* prior the user's explicit consent for the transmission of personal information abroad.

Anonymous navigation information is also used for the following purposes:  

* statistical related to the creation of consumer and user profiles utilized to ensure efficient management of the site or by third parties with whom kidscantravel.com has entered into commercial agreements to effect directed advertising campaigns and improve the efficiency and effectiveness of said campaigns; 
* commercial, marketing, market research, and [advertising](http://www.kidscantravel.com/legal/index.html#6I) relating to the kidscantravel.com service or that of third party advertisers as well as communicating anonymous user related navigation information with third parties with whom kidscantravel.com has entered into commercial agreements; 
* determine the quality of the service offered by kidscantravel.com and degree of user satisfaction, carried out both directly and with the help of specialized third parties;

Personal information related to the user that is consensually provided is also used for following purposes:  

* prior the user's explicit consent, for kidscantravel.com operational and management needs. 

**d. Right of refusal**  
Failure to provide the personal information referred to in points b and c hereinabove, where requested, is of no consequence other than the inability to make use of those services and procedures for which the provision of personal information is indispensable.   

**e. Communicating and divulging data**  
kidscantravel.com does not divulge any personal information related to the user provided consensually for the purpose of registration nor does it divulge any anonymous navigation information pertaining to the user which is either provided or collected during the course of navigation with any third parties. 

kidscantravel.com may communicate anonymous navigation information to third parties with whom it has entered into commercial agreements. The eventual communication of information is expressly limited to anonymous navigation information and personal information related to the user as set out in point b1 hereof. The communication of anonymous navigation information and personal information related to the user is communicated in an aggregated form.   
Upon request, kidscantravel.com shall necessarily make the user's personal information available to the Judicial Authority's disposal. kidscantravel.com reserves the right to disclose said information in those instances in which the user's activity is in breach of the Legal Notice set out herein.  
Owing to the generic nature of the Internet it should be noted that any information provided voluntarily by the user may be used both in EU and non-EU countries reached by the network.   

**f. User rights**  
As regards the usage of personal information the user may exercise those rights set out in art.7 of Italian Decree law No 196 dated June 30, 2003, amongst which that of obtaining confirmation of the existence or not of their personal information and their communication in an intelligible form.  
The user has the right to know: 

* origin of information and usage 
* usage 
* usage carried out through electronic means 
* subjects or categories of subjects with whom personal information may be communicated or who may become aware of it as principle, delegate, or designated representative.
  
Moreover, the user has the right to request:  

* subjects or categories of subjects with whom personal information may be shared or who may become aware of it as principle, delegate, or designated representative.
  
Moreover, the user has the right to request that:  

* information be updated, corrected and integrated 
* cancellation, transformation into an anonymous form or blockage of any information used in breach of the law, including information that need not be kept for those purposes for which it was collected or subsequently utilized 
* confirmation that the hereinabove has been brought to the attention, even as regards their contents, of those to whom the information has been communicated , except those cases in which said fulfillment proves impossible or involves the use of disproportionate means compared to the right protected.

The user has the right to oppose, in whole or in part:  

* usage of their personal information, for legitimate reasons, even if pertinent to the purposes for which it was collected; 
* usage of their personal information to send advertising or direct sales material or to carry out market research or commercial communications. 

The Privacy Guarantor has established, per its ruling No 14 dated December 23, 2004, the cost attributable to users exercising their right of access to personal information. 

* The amount equal to €10 in all cases in which it is impossible to confirm the existence of data. 
* The amount equal to €2.50 in all cases in which data is processed electronically and a negative response is provided verbally. 
* Free of charge in all cases in which the existence of personal data is confirmed. 
* A maximum of €20 for the reproduction by electronic means (audiovisual, tape or other magnetic support) on which the user's personal data is already present. 

**g. Exercising user rights**  
Those rights set out in point f. hereinabove may be exercised in accordance with the means indicated in art.9 of Italian Decree law no.196 of June 30, 2003, and, in any case, by directing specific requests to [privacy@kidscantravel.com](mailto:privacy@kidscantravel.com).   

**h. Handling of personal information**  
more2explore S.r.l. with registered offices in Via Giulini 5, Monza 20052 Italy, is responsible for the processing of personal information and has delegated this activity to its pro-tempore legal representative Ms. Ann Marie LoCicero. The list of individuals currently designated by the company to process personal information is available from [privacy@kidscantravel.com](mailto:privacy@kidscantravel.com).   

**i. Changes to statement**  
more2explore S.r.l. reserves the right to modify this document. Personal information used in any other way other than that specified in the statement available at the time of collection shall be highlighted, by kidscantravel.com, to the user by updating the date shown below the link to the **Legal Notice** and **Privacy** located at the bottom of each page.  
Subsequent usage of the service shall constitute acceptance of the Legal Notice and Privacy policy as updated and modified.   

**j. Links**  
This statement applies solely to kidscantravel.com and is not applicable to those website accessible by hyperlink and/or offered or present on the site.   

**k. Certification of translation**  
This statement has been translated to English from the Italian original; this English-language translation has been legalized by the Court of Monza, Italy as certified below and is in conformity with the Italian-language original.   

Click on image to enlarge

**CONSENT**

The user declares to have read the Legal Notice governing this web site, to have received complete information in accordance with art.13 of Italian Decree law no. 196 of June 30, 2003, is aware of his/her rights and agrees in accordance with art.23 of Italian Decree law no 196 of June 30, 2003, to the usage and communication of his/her personal information for those purposes and by those means indicated herein. This consent may be revoked at any time using the cancellation procedures set up on the site, as well as present on the newsletter service. The user further acknowledges that kidscantravel.com requires email confirmation from the user prior to effecting any registrations, modifications or cancellation. The user may contact [privacy@kidscantravel.com](mailto:privacy@kidscantravel.com) should they encounter any registration or cancellation difficulties.   
To exercise those rights set out in Italian Decree law No 196/2003 the user shall submit a written request via email to [privacy@kidscantravel.com](mailto:privacy@kidscantravel.com).   

|    
---|---|---
